The more...the scarier!
Cheaper by the Dozen is a comedy, family, drama film directed by Shawn Levy.
The Baker brood moves to Chicago after patriarch Tom gets a job coaching football at Northwestern
University, forcing his writer wife, Kate, and the couple's 12 children to make a major adjustment.
The transition works well until work demands pull the parents away from
home, leaving the kids bored -- and increasingly mischievous.
Tom Baker, played by Steve Martin.
Kate Baker, played by Bonnie Hunt.
Lorraine Baker, played by Hilary Duff.
Charlie Baker, played by Tom Welling.
Nora Baker, played by Piper Perabo.
Henry Baker, played by Kevin G. Schmidt.
Cheaper by the Dozen is a 2003 American comedy film directed by Shawn Levy.
It is a remake of the 1950 film of the same name.
Both films were inspired by the semi-autobiographical book
Cheaper by the Dozen by Frank Bunker Gilbreth Jr.
and his sister Ernestine Gilbreth Carey.
It stars Steve Martin, Bonnie Hunt, Hilary Duff, Tom
Welling, and Piper Perabo, alongside Kevin G.
Schmidt, Alyson Stoner, Jacob Smith, Forrest Landis, Liliana Mumy, Morgan York, Blake
Woodruff, Brent and Shane Kinsman, Paula Marshall, and Alan Ruck in supporting roles.
Outside of a passing mention of the Gilbreth name, the film has
little connection with the original source material.
The film was released on December 25, 2003, by 20th Century Fox and
grossed $190 million worldwide against a $40 million budget.
The Rotten Tomatoes critical consensus criticized
the film for its lack of humor.
A sequel, Cheaper by the Dozen 2, was released in 2005.
A remake was released in 2022 on Disney+.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, husband wife relationship,
based on novel or book, american football coach, big family.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.